Finding Aid for the Olive Percival Papers LSC.0119
UCLA Library Special Collections
- 20. Framed Pictures
  - Photograph of standing grave-stones on a grassy hill., Item 1 (Box 31)
    Mounted on white mat upon which OP has written, ink, "In memory of Mrs. Elizabeth, wife of Mr. Levi Robinson, who died Oct. 19, 1820, AE. 59 years." etc. On back OP has noted, ink: "Gt.-Gt.-Grandfather. Levi Robinson of Lee, Berkshire County, Massachusetts - Soldier of the Revolution." 22 × 15 cm. Narrow wood mold frame.
  - Photograph of large globular basket with two women inside, on a lawn., Item 2 (Box 31)
    OP noted, ink, on back: "The famous Granary Basket/when in the collection of Belle Jewett, Towanda Park 1895/J.Torrey Connor/Olive Percival." In pencil "See my article in Democrat." Narrow dark wood frame. 13 × 15 cm.
  - Group photograph, in front of half-timbered house., Item 3 (Box 31)
    OP seated on grass in mid-foreground holding striped cat. OP has written, ink, on back: "My Wild-Flower-Viewing Party" followed by a list of names of other women in the photograph. Pencil, near top right "Apl./1905." In small dark wood frame. 7.5 × 10.5 cm.
  - Photograph., Item 4 (Box 31)
    "Obadiah Graves - of Lee, Massachusetts. B. 30 April, 1771 D. 6 June, 1859 - My Great.Grandsire. Taken a. 1845-" Identification in ink by OP on back. Gild wood frame. 13 × 10 cm.
  - Photograph., Item 5 (Box 31)
    "Father's Cousin, Cora Graves - of Lee, Mass. - Aet. 16 - Cora at 16 - 1864 -" Identification on back, ink, by OP. Oval, brass and wood frame. 12 cm. high.
  - Photograph., Item 6 (Box 31)
    "Father's cousin - Cora Graves Aet.3 - 1851 [?] -" Identification on back, ink, by OP. Oval, Brass and wood frame, 10 cm. high.
  - Portrait. Olive Percival. Pastel sketch by May Curran., Item 7 (Box 1)
    Los Angeles, c. 1901. Gift of H. Richard Archer, Jan. 1945. [Identification on back]. Plain gilt frame. 43 × 36 cm.
  - Photograph of young man., Item 8 (Box 31)
    Inscribed in ink on mat: "To La Percivale: in loving memory: November 1911. GWP." On back, a label, in ink, by OP, "George Plank of Philadelphia c. 1909." 31.5 × 23.5 cm. [See 119/4/10] "See cuts 119/21/2 - 4, 7, 13, etc.]
  - Photograph of OP in costume standing at spinning wheel in front of fireplace., Item 9 (Box 31)
    Inscribed by OP: "For Polly/With much love/Olive Percival/ 1902" 10.5 × 13 cm.
  - Photograph of OP in costume standing at cupboard from which she is taking a teapot., Item 10; 12 × 7 cm. (Box 7)
  - Photograph of OP seated on fallen log over a stream, holding a Japanese parasol over her head., Item 11 (Box 31)
    OP has noted, ink, on back: "At my Wild Flower Viewing in April 1905." In pencil below "(O.P.)" Framed in small dark wood frame. 11.5 × 9 cm.
  - Photograph of Mrs. Percival seated in wicker chair, back to camera., Item 12 (Box 31)
    OP has noted, ink, on back: "My dear Mother on The Terrace with her Newspaper / Aet. 78 / April 1925." Framed in black and gilt wooden frame with metal loop at top for hanging. 23 × 17.5 cm.
  - Photograph of young girl., Item 13 (Box 31)
    OP has noted, ink, on back: "Cora Graves (Father's Cousin)." Framed in narrow dark wood molding with oval mat of gilt metal. Metal ring at top for hanging. 9.5 × 8.5 cm.
  - Photograph of Mrs. John Howard Percival and her son., Item 14 (Box 31)
    On back is a small decorative label with initials "O.P.", upon which OP has noted, ink, "Mother and Brother Leo." Brown veneer frame, with metal ring at top for hanging. 11 × 7 cm.
  - Print of bookplate "Ex Libris Olive May Graves Percival" with the motto "Sub cruce canto", by E. H. New,., 1919; Item 15 (Box 31)
    Signed in lower left corner "Edmund H. New". Note, ink, by OP on back "The Percival Place, Lenox, Massachusetts/ Built 1773 by Capt. Elisha Percival..." etc. Gilt wood frame. 19 × 14 cm.
  - Photograph of kettle on a table., Item 16 (Box 31)
    OP has noted, ink, on back: "The Dickens Kettle used at God's Will. Bought of his sister-in-law, Miss Georgina Hogarth..." etc. Wood frame. 16 × 28 cm.
  - Original drawing for book plate "Olive Percival her book" [showing woman in sedan chair buying books in front of The Blew Anchor] by Jay Chambers "-19-"., Item 17 (Box 31)
    OP has noted, pencil, on back "(Framed by Wm. O'Kane!) Jay Chambers - Pupil of Howard Pyle." Unfinished mold frame. 31 × 24 cm.
  - Photograph. Helen Mason Percival, mother of Olive Percival., Item 18 (Box 2)
    Identified on back, ink, by OP: "My Mother c. 1891 - Helen Mason Percival - 12 Sept. 1846 - 13 Feb. 1928." Wood and gilt oval frame. 36 × 30 cm.
  - Photograph. Mrs. Percival [probably in garden at The Down-hyl Claim]., No date.; Item 19 (Box 31)
    Inserted in large oval locket, gold wash. Lock of hair behind glass at back of locket. Locket encased in small bag with green ribbon drawstrings. 8 cm.
  - Photograph. Olive Percival in her garden., Not dated.; Item 20 (Box 31)
    Oval, 10 cm. high. Gilt metal frame. Encased in purple velvet bag with silk ribbon strings.
  - Rubbing., Item 21 (Box 31)
    Identified, ink, by OP on face. "Cousin Della Graves made this rubbing from the headstone of Fear Percival's-- Lenox (Cong/1) Burying ground. October 1903/ Fear Percival Died 11 May, 1815 Aet. 28/" Gilt and painted wood frame. [See article in The Graphic, p. 3 July 18, 1914. and printed articles 119/1.]
  - Photograph of OP dressed in Japanese costume, kneeling on cushion, with tea bowls and other Japanese furniture about her., Item 22 (Box 7)
    18 × 12.5 cm. OP has written in pencil on back: "Olive Percival/1901"
  - Photograph of OP (head and shoulders) wearing plumed hat., Item 23; Oval gilt frame. 8 × 6 cm. (Box 7)
  - Photograph of lady (OP's mother?) in garden behind sundial., Item 24 (Box 7)
    Small oval frame, gilt and enamel, containing photo of lady (OP's mother?) in garden behind the sundial. 4.5 × 4 cm. In blue pongee bag with lavender and white satin ribbon draw strings.
    [Note: Items 22 thru 24 Gift of Mrs. Morris Cohn (Edith Armer)]
  - Photograph of OP in old fashioned dress sitting before fireplace, with spinning wheel in left background., Item 25 (Box 7)
    Noted on back: "Grandmother/Percival's/Spinning/Wheel-/1901." and "O.P./1901." in white enameled wood frame. 10 × 12-1/2 cm.
  - Photograph of CP., Item 26 (Box 7)
    Photograph of CP in old fashioned costume with lace shawl and bonnet, seated on bench outside of doorway. Noted on back: "O.P. & her/Godey Book/Bonnet-/c. 1905-/ (Bonnet from/Attic of Gt.-Gt./-Aunt Sally Foote/Lee, Mass./1903-" In walnut frame lightly mottled with gold. 12 × 10 cm.
  - Photograph (head and shoulders) of OP in profile., Item 27 (Box 7)
    Inscribed below, pencil, "Yours,/Olive Percival/For my dear Iris Lady-". In dark wood frame. 16 × 11-1/2 cm.
  - Photograph (blue printed) of OP standing in garden - dressed in old fashioned striped dress standing with her back to the camera., Item 28 (Box 7)
    Dress has been tinted greenish blue, OP's shoulders and arm tinted pink. Gilt frame. 12 × 9-1/2 cm.
    [Note: Items 25 thru 28 gift of Mrs. Morris Cohn (Edith Armer)]
- [Miscellaneous]
  - Photographs (Box 10)
    Several envelopes:
    Residential Interior (fireplaces, etc.)
    Envelope of blue-colored snapshots of exteriors of various residences
    Framed photo of Miss Percival
    Silver envelope of several photos of winter scenes
  - Large Photographs (Box 10)
    Mr. & Mrs. J.G. Mossin in Japan, 1906
    Dining room table, 1912
    Miss Percival at spinning wheel; "The Ark" at La Jolla, undated
    "Mother at 77", 1923
    "Mrs. Taft" with cat, 1912
    Other photos [miscellaneous] of doorways, cats, pastoral scenes, blue photos of houses, lamp
    Small envelope with several photos of "Hildegarde F." and Alice Millard.
    Framed portrait of O.P. inscribed to "Mother".
    Other envelopes of photos.
  - Negatives, Loose: (Box 10)
    1914: 1
    1923: 11
    1925: 6
    1931: 4
    1933: 3
    1934: 11
    1935: 3
    1936: 10
    1937: 2
    1938: 25
    1940: 2
    1941: 3
    Undated: 5.
    Total 86. Also: Several envelopes, some with negatives, some empty.
  - Textiles (Box 10)
    Numerous samples and small bags.
  - Painting of woman [O.P.?] with head turned away. (Box 10)
  - Clippings, Envelopes, Poster with poem by Carrie Jacobs Bond. (Box 10)
  - Letter re: Englishmen being sent to farms in Canada, [1905]; Item 1 (Box 11)
  - Clippings. Furniture and Accessories [garden]., Item 2 (Box 11)
  - Clippings. of Flower Monographs., Item 3 (Box 11)
  - Clippings. on Botanical Gardens., Item 4 (Box 11)
  - Clippings. of Flower Arrangements., Item 5 (Box 11)
  - Clippings. of Garden Miscellany., Item 6 (Box 11)
  - Clippings. from Pacific Garden., Item 7 (Box 11)
  - Clippings. on Bulbs and Vines., Item 8 (Box 11)
  - Clippings. on flowers., Item 9 (Box 11)
  - Clippings. on Garden arrangements., Item 10 (Box 11)
  - Clippings. on Garden arrangements (part 2)., Item 11 (Box 11)
  - Clippings. on Roses., Item 12 (Box 11)
  - Clippings. of Narratives on Little gardens., Item 13 (Box 11)
  - Clippings on Irises and Daffodils; Lilies; Flower Arrangements; Garden Architecture; trees; flower lore; Garden accessories. (Box 12)
  - Scrapbooks.
    - Price Lists., Item 1 (Box 13)
    - Poetry and Porcelain., Item 2 (Box 13)
    - List of Gifts (?)., Item 3 (Box 13)
    - Handbags., Item 4 (Box 13)
    - Menus., Item 5 (Box 13)
    - Horoscope., Item 6 (Box 13)
    - Parodies., Item 7 (Box 13)
    - Poems about Books., Item 8 (Box 13)
    - Newspaper clippings., Item 9 (Box 13)
    - Personal photograph album., Item 10 (Box 13)
    - Clippings., Item 11 (Box 13)
    - Leaves from "Day with Joaquin Miller" with Miller autograph??, Item 12 (Box 13)
    - Clippings: How to cook with herbs., Item 13 (Box 13)
    - "Unusual" names., Item 14 (Box 13)
    - Bookbindings., Item 15 (Box 13)
    - The House of Ramona, Item 16 (Box 13)
    - Clippings of use of Chafing dish., Item 17 (Box 13)
  - "The Childlover's Calander"., (cover only) (Box 14)
  - "Books unable to obtain." (Box 14)
  - "My Lady's Toilette Table". (Box 14)
  - "Winds of the World"., [book] (Box 14)
  - Booklists. (Box 14)
  - "Credo", concerning William Vaughan Moody. (Box 14)
  - New Republic., May 23, 1934. (Box 14)
  - The Measure. [Journal of Poetry] (Box 14)
  - The Galleon., July, 1924. (Box 14)
  - "Among Quiet friends." (Box 14)
  - "Impressions.", 17 copies. (Box 14)
  - Book Review Clippings. (Box 14)
  - Ideas for Children's Bookplates. (Box 14)
  - Clippings on Books and Bookbinding [for children]. (Box 14)
  - Clippings on Food, Menus, Household clippings, table chats, simple living, decorating, artists, handicrafts, art clippings, antiques. (Box 15)
  - Clippings: Theatre, Art and Art Exhibits, Art of Theatre, Film, Essay Clippings. (Box 16)
  - Notes: Japan and its arts; notes on Japan, clippings on Japan, Japanese exclusion question. (Box 17)
  - The Shosho-In by Sir Percival David, Bart., [pamphlet]. (Box 17)
  - The Japanese Magazine. [2 copies] (Box 17)
  - Folder of Japanese art. (Box 17)
  - Asia Magazine., [1931]. (Box 17)
  - Travel in Japan [magazine]. (Box 17)
  - Clippings from the L.A. Times (Box 18)
    Famous birthdays [several hundred clippings from the L.A. Times]; Misc. local people; Obituaries on Anabella Rodman, Clippings on Pauline Curran, Mildred Brooks, Margaret Fowler, Mrs. Hobart Bosworth, The George Millards, Natalie Curtis, Wilbur Macy Stone, Frank L. Wright.
  - Clippings
    - From Boston Evening Transcript., Item 1 (Box 19)
    - Religious nature., Item 2 (Box 19)
    - New York City., Item 3 (Box 19)
    - Sea and Ship life., Item 4 (Box 19)
  - Numerous photos, etc. (Box 19)
  - Art prints and miscellaneous clippings an art. (Box 20)
  - Paper samples, paper dolls; clippings on singers, pets; paper cut-outs; correspondence, etc. (Box 21)
  - Clippings on Trees, Current Events and World History, Flower Arrangements, General Articles. (Box 22)
  - Over 1000 poems clipped or copied, personal papers, miscellaneous clippings. (Box 23)
  - Letters to Mrs. F.M. Kreider re: Olive Percival., Item 1 (Box 24)
    from:
    "Alice R.S."
    Florence Bixby
    Mrs. Chas. H.Wright
    W. Summer Appleton [for the Society for the Preservation of New England Antiquities]
    George Plank [with enclosures]
    Netta Marquis
    Mira C. Saunders
    Mary Halliday
    Ernest Dawson
    "Rachel" [540 Toro Cañon Road, Santa Barbara].
  - Various other correspondence., Item 2 (Box 24)
  - Clippings., Item 3 (Box 24)
  - Box of clippings of cats., Item 4 (Box 24)
  - Copy of Old-time New England [Bulletin of the Society for the Preservation of New England Antiquities]., Item 5 (Box 24)
  - Bill for printing Old-fashioned flowers., Item 6 (Box 24)
  - Partial list of items packed for the New England Society for the Preservation of Antiquities., Item 7 (Box 24)
  - Book review of Our old-fashioned lowers, [by O.P.] [Pasadena Star-News, Sept. 7, 1947.]; Item 8 (Box 24)
  - Letter to O.P. from Eber C. Byam., Item 9 (Box 24)
  - Announcement to O.P. from Geo. M. Millard., Item 10 (Box 24)
  - Clippings re: Eugene Field., Item 11 (Box 24)
  - Valentines, Bookplates, Christmas cards, corresp. Gift of Leda Klauber., Item 12 (Box 24)
  - Clippings re: Gloria Vanderbilt, et. al., Item 13 (Box 24)
  - Box including clippings, paper dolls, photos, and manuscript of translations of Chinese poems., Item 14 (Box 24)
  - Index to books in Olive Percival's collection of children's books. (Box 25)
  - Clippings, ephemera, pictures, and plates for pictures, all relating to Olive Percival and her collection. (Box 26)
  - Transcripts of Olive Percival's diary. (Box 27, 28, 29, 32, 33)
    Also in negative microfilm, #02601.
  - Original zinc blocks made for Olive Percival's pictures and designs. (Box 30)
  - Pictures of, and relating to, Olive Percival. (Box 31)
    [See pp. 40, 41.]
  - Picture of Olive Percival. (Box 35)
  - Picture of Olive Percival's mother. (Box 35)
  - Bookplates from Olive Percival's collection. (Box 36 - 45, 9)
- 22. Negative collection.
  Note
  A small selection of these nitrate negatives were digitized and are available through the UCLA Digital Library. The remainder of nitrate negatives were disposed of due to degradation.
  - Wooden box containing some 2,000 negatives (some glass) of photos taken by Miss Percival.
    Gift of Mrs. Florence Kreider.
- 21. Miscellaneous Objects
  - Chest., Item 1
    Wood, covered with hide [hair nearly all gone]. Lined with old newspaper. Brass handle on top. Hasp broken. Key lacking. When received contained book plate cuts.
  - Collection of 46 cuts., Item 2
    Gift of Mrs. Florence Kreider, executrix of Olive Percival. Cuts for book plates, Christmas cards, etc., some for OP, some for other persons. When received many of the cuts were badly corroded. These have been cleaned and coated with vaseline. For prints made from some of these cuts, see Series 17: Items 1-35.
- [22.] Music Books
  Gift of Zeitlin & Ver Brugge, 1948-49.
  - 1. Bliss, P.P. Welcome Tidings: a new collection of sacred songs... New York: Biglaw & Main, 1877.; 13.5 × 17.5 cm. 160pp.
    Scope and Content
    OP's music plate inside front cover; noted in ink on first leaf: [1877]/ This is the song-book used in my later/Sunday School Days (1879-1885)-/Congregational Church-/Sheffield, Ill.-
  - 2. O'Kane, T.C. Jasper and gold. New York: Phillips & Hunt, 1877.; 160pp. 14 × 18 cm.
    OP's music plate inside front cover. Signed in ink inside front cover, Olive Percival with pencil note below: (This was From the M.E. S.S)/ 45¢/.
  - 3. Lawry, Robert Royal Diadem for the Sunday School. New York and Chicago: Biglaw & Main, 1873.; 160pp. 13.5 × 17.5 cm.
    OP's music plate inside front cover. Note in ink on first leaf 'Royal Diadem-'/ obsolete in my Sunday School Days/ but sometimes used at Concerts and, Christmas Trees-/ Sheffield, Illinois.
  - 4. Bradbury, William B. Fresh Laurels for the Sabbath School. New York: Biglow & Main, 1867.; 160pp. 13 × 17 cm.
    OP's music plate inside front cover. Note in ink on piece of note paper pasted in front of title pages 'Fresh Laurels'/ used in Congregational Sunday School/ in the 1860s and, 1870s-/ From the old Choir Gallery (in disuse)/ about 1885-/ Sheffield-Ill.
  - 5. Emerson, L.0. The Standard. A collection of sacred and secular music... New York: C.H. Ditson & Company, 1872.; 399pp. 16.5 × 26.5 cm.; OP's music plate inside front cover.
  - 6. Zeuner, Ch. The Ancient lyre, a collection of old, new, and original church music. Boston: Crocker and Brewster, 1837.; 358 numbered pages, plus index. 16 × 25 cm.
    OP's music plate inside front cover, also OP's gift plate with ink notation: Gt.-Gt.- Aunt Sally Percival Foote's Attic -/ Lee-Mass. 1903.
  - 7. Boston Academy. The Boston Academy's Collection of Church Music., [Title page missing] Pages numbered 4-354. Full leather binding. 15.5 × 25 cm.
    OP's music plate inside front cover, also OP's gift player with ink notations Gt.-Gt.-Aunt/Sally Percival Foote's/Attic-/Lee-/Mass. 1903.
  - 8. Bradbury, William B. The Jubilees an extensive collection of church music. New York: Mason Brothers, 1858.; 384pp. 17 × 25 cm.
    OP's music plate inside front cover, also OP's gift plate with ink notations Marcella/Day/Byam-/L.X.- 1931. Pencil note inside front cover at bottom: From/Marcella Byam- 1931-1 whose father (N.M. Day-Byam)/sang in the M.E. Choir-/ in the Pioneer Days of Linn Co.- Iowa.
  - 9. Partington, Violet, compiler and arranger. French songs. London: J.K. Dent & Sons, 1916.; 42pp. 18 × 12 cm.; OP's music plate inside front cover.
  - 10. Chicago. David C. Cook, publisher. The Advanced Scholar, 1882.; Bound in purple paper back by OP. 21.5 × 16.5 cm.
    First, second, third and fourth quarters.
    OP plate inside front cover, with note in ink on paper slip attached The Advanced Scholar (4)/ - 1882-/These are very precious remembrances/ of our Sabbeth School Days in/the old white Congregational Meeting-/house in Sheffield, Illinois./ The Superintendents were/Albert W. Boyden/ Rev. G.K. Colman/Joseph A. Mercer/B.F. Dewey/ My beloved Teachers were/ Mrs. A.W. Boyden and,/ James George.
  - 11. Chicago. Abraham Lincoln Centre. Unity Festivals., 1905.; 118pp. 23 × 15.5 cm.
    OP's music plate inside front cover. Pencil note at bottom of first leaf Christmas Carols/ p.84 et seq.
  - 12. Tomlins, W.L., editor. The Laurel Music-Reader. Boston: C.C. Birchard & Company, 1912.; 154pp. 27 × 18 cm.; OP's music plate inside front cover.
  - 13. Griggs, Herbert, compiler. The Beacon song collection number two. Boston: Silver, Burdett & Company, 1900.; 252pp., plus index. 24 × 18.5 cm.; OP's music plate inside front cover.
  - 14. Warren, George William Hymns and tunes as sung at St. Thomas's church, New York. New York: Harper & Brothers, 1888.; 93pp. 26.5 × 18.5 cm.
    OP's music marker inside front cover. Pencil note at top of first leaf: (From dearest little Cousin Ruth Graves).
  - 15. Dare, George S., compiler. Everybody's Song Book. New York: A.S. Barnes and Company, 1938.; 174pp. 26 × 19 cm.; OP's music plate inside front cover.
  - 16. Felton, William M. Grown-up beginner's book. Philadelphia: Theodore Presser Company, 1935.; 97pp. Paper cover. 30 × 23 cm.; OP's music plate inside front cover.
  - 17. American Tract Company Songs of Zion. Enlarged. New York: American Tract Company, 1864.; 384pp. 15.5 × 11 cm. Signed, ink, first leaf Mrs. D.H. Colcord.
  - 18: Mudge, Lewis W. compiler. Carmina for the Sunday School. New Edition. New York: A.S. Barnes & Company, 1898.; 293pp., plus index. 15 × 19 cm.
    Stamped inside front covers Property of Claremont Cong. S.S.
  - 19. Emerson, L.O. The Hour of singing. Boston: Oliver Ditson & Company, 1871.; 240pp. 15 × 22.5 cm.
  - 20. Boston Academy. The Boston Academy's collection of church music. Boston: Carter, Hendee & Company, 1835.; 357pp. Plus index. 16 × 25 cm.; Signed, pencil, upper right of title page: Mrs. D.H. Colcord.
  - 21. Mason, Lowell. Carmina Sacra: or Boston collection of church music. New York: Mason Brothers, 1841.; 348 numbered pages, index, 32 numbered pages. 15 × 24.5 cm.
  - 22. Leslie, C.E. The Conqueror. Chicago: The Chicago Music Company, 1880.; 159pp., plus index. 17 × 26 cm.; Signed, green ink, at top of first leaf: Miss Hattie Beau Jean Feby 9 1884.
  - 23. Emerson, L.O. The Choral tribute. Boston: Oliver Ditson & Company, 1869.; 400 p. 17 × 25 cm.; Signed, pencil, inside front covert E.A. Veasie/ Apr 1874.
  - 24. Robinson, Charles Seymour, ed. Laudes Domini. New York: The Century Company, 1888.; 16 × 20 cm.
  - 25. Voices of Praise [title page missing]., 411pp. 21 × 14.5 cm.; Signed, pencil, at top first pages D.H. Colcord, Claremont, Cal.
  - 26. Hymns of worship and service, chapel edition, New York: The Century Company, 1908.; 21.5 × 15.5 cm.; Signed, ink, first leaf D.H. Colcord, 1908.
  - 27. Hitchcock, Roswell D., editor. Hymns and songs for social and sabbath worship. New York: A.S. Barnes & Company, 1886.; 145pp. 19 × 16 cm.; Signed, ink, on first leaf: D.H. Colcord.
  - 28. Turner, Herbert B., editor. Hymns and tunes for schools. New York: A.S. Barnes & Company, 1907.; 20 × 15.5 cm.
  - 29. Congregational Sunday-School and Publishing Society. The Pilgrim Hymnal with responsive readings. Boston: The Pilgrim Press, 1904.; 631pp. 21.5 × 15.5 cm.; Signed, ink, on second leaf: D.H. Colcord.
  - 30. MacArthur, Robert Stuart, editor. In Excelsis. Hymns with tunes for Christian worship. New York: The Century Company, 1900.; 737pp. 22 × 15.5 cm.
  - 31. Waite, Henry Randall, editor. Carmina collegensia: a complete collection of the songs of the American colleges. Boston: Oliver Ditson & Company, 1876.; 88pp. 26 × 19 cm.; Signed, pencil, at top of title page: M.C. Post.
  - 32. Biglow & Main. Gospel Hymns. Chicago: Biglow & Main, 1883.; 400pp. 21.5 × 13.5 cm.; O.Percival in a circular design stenciled on cover. O.P.'s music plate inside front cover.; Signed, pencil, at top of title page Olive Percival (1883)/ Sheffield/ Ills.
  - 33. Hitchcock, Roswell D., editor. Hymns and songs of praise. New York: Anson D.F. Randolph & Company, 1874.; 603pp. 21.5 × 16 cm.; OP's book plate inside front cover.; Signed, pencil, first leaf Mrs. J.H. Percival/(About 1877).; Has been covered with a reddish paper wrapper.
    Three notes by OP laid in back. [In envelope with miscellaneous 119/12].
  - 34. Root, George F. The Flower Queen. Boston: Oliver Ditson & Company, 1852.; 102pp. 15 × 22.5 cm.; OP's music plate inside front cover.; Signed, pencil, on first leaf Olive Percival/Los Angeles/ 1915.
  - 35. Part of song book., Pages numbered 93-366. 16 × 24.5 cm.; No cover, no title page, no identifying marks.
  - 36. Waite, Henry Randall, compiler. College songs. Boston: Oliver Ditson Company, 1906.; 128pp. 25.5 × 17 cm.; OP's music plate inside front cover.; Signed, ink, at top of front cover Olive Percival.
  - 37. McCaskey, J.P., compiler. Franklin Square song collection. New York: American Book Company, 1881.; 184pp. 24.5 × 17 cm.; OP's music plate inside front cover.; In ink, on first leaf To alive/ from Helen.
  - 38. Jones, Walter Howe, compiler. New songs for male quartets. New York: Hinds, Noble & Eldredge., 57pp. 24.5 × 18.5 cm.; OP's music plate inside front cover.
  - 39. Hoff, William C., compiler. The Corona song book. Boston: Ginn & Company, 1903.; 362pp. 28 × 19.5 cm.; Flowered chintz cover sewn over book.; OP's music plate inside front cover.
  - 40. Songs that never grow old. New York: Syndicate publishing company, 1913.; 256pp. 25.5 × 18.5.; OP's music plate inside front cover.
    Written by OP in ink at top of first leaf From Cousin Julia Graves/ Christmas/ 1914.
  - 41. Tufts, John W., compiler. The Euterpean. Silver, Burdett & Company, 1888.; 264pp. 26.5 × 20 cm.
  - 42. Bound volume, labeled Music, containing sheet music., Binding loose. 35 × 26.5 cm.